A Guide to the Lewis W. Hackett Papers FA043
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Lewis W. Hackett Photographs, Negatives, and Slides, 1914-1949; 1071; 41 box(es)
  - Photographs, 1
    - Photographs -- Loose Photographs, 1.1
      - Roll Lists (Box 8, Folder 62)
      - Portraits - Lewis W. Hackett -- Individual (Box 9, Folder 63)
      - Portraits - Lewis W. Hackett -- Group (Box 9, Folder 64)
        Small Format
      - Portraits - Lewis W. Hackett -- Group (Box 9, Folder 65)
        Medium, Large Format
      - Portraits - Individuals (Box 9, Folder 66)
        Unknown Individuals
      - Portraits - Individuals (Box 9, Folder 67)
        Identified Individuals
      - Portraits - Groups (Box 9, Folder 68)
        Identified Groups
      - Portraits - Groups (Box 9, Folder 69)
        Unidentified Groups
    - Lewis W. Hackett Photograph Collection - Photographs -- Albums, 1.2
      - Album I - Albania (1931), Bethlehem, Dead Sea, Egypt, Jerusalem, Palestine (Box 10)
      - Album II - Identified Portraits, Greece (Box 11)
      - Album III - Algiers, Corsica, Spain (Box 11)
      - Album IV - Christmas Album, Panama, 1914 (Box 11)
      - Album V - Ellis Park, Lake Tahoe (1911), Miscellaneous Portraits, Miscellaneous, Duplicates (Box 12)
      - Album VI - Family Album (Box 13)
      - Album VII - Italy - Egypt Trip, 1938 (Box 14)
      - Album VIII - Rolls 87-93, Latin America (Box 15)
      - Album IX - Albania, Algiers, Argentina, Bolivia (Box 16)
      - Album IX - Brazil, Canada, Chile, Czechoslovakia, Egypt, Ecuador, England, Germany, Greece, Holland, Hungary, Italy (Box 17)
      - Album IX - Malaya, Manaus, Mexico, Peru, Uruguay, United States, Venezuela, Yugoslavia (Box 18)
      - Album X - Albania (1936), Czechoslovakia, England, Greece, Holland, Hungary, Italy, Mexico (1936), Switzerland (1937), United States, Yugoslavia (Box 19)
      - Album XI - Albania (1935), Germany, Hungary, Sicily, Yugoslavia (Box 20)
    - Lewis W. Hackett Photograph Collection - Photographs -- Mounted Prints, 1.3
      Scope and Contents
      This Mounted Prints subseries contains 15 Hackett photographs that have been enlarged and matted.
      - Italy (Box 21)
      - Albania (Box 22)
  - Negatives, 2
    - Negatives -- Loose Negatives, 2.1
      - Brazil (Group A and Group B), Ceylon, Guatemala, Italy/France, Java - Philippines, India (Box 23)
      - Panama, Siam, Sumatra, US - Georgia, Personal/Films, Glass Negatives, Negatives/Contacts (Box 24)
      - Negatives/Contacts (Box 25, Folder 70)
        Unidentified, Miscellaneous
      - Negatives/Contacts (Box 25, Folder 71)
      - Negatives/Contacts (Box 25, Folder 72)
        Unidentified, Miscellaneous Contact Strips
      - Negatives/Contacts (Box 25, Folder 73)
      - Negatives/Contacts (Box 25, Folder 74)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 25, Folder 75)
        Unidentified, Miscellaneous Argentina, Death Valley
      - Miscellaneous (Box 25, Folder 76)
        Unidentified, Miscellaneous Hackett Family
    - Negatives -- Negative Albums, 2.2
      The Negative Albums in this subseries are arranged in the order that L.W. Hackett intended. Each album is complete with a list identifying the negatives contained therein. These negative albums have corresponding prints that have been extracted and foldered. The albums and folders are housed together for cross-referencing. There appears to have been an original series of 1-13, but the existing series begins with number 4 and is missing number 9. Album 6 is missing, but the negatives remain in order and the identification list is contained in the folder. This subseries also includes a negative album that is not part of the numbered series described above. It is housed separately in box 29 and contains identification of all photos.
      - Negative Album 4 - Basilicata (Box 26, Folder 77)
        Basilicata, negative album, corresponding prints in order of list in album
      - Negative Album 5 - Sardegna (Sardinia) (Box 26, Folder 78)
      - Negative Album 6 - Albania (Box 26, Folder 79)
        Albania. Corresponding prints not identified; folder contains negatives in order of list removed from album.
      - Negative Album 7 - Italy (Box 27, Folder 80)
        Italy. Numbered prints removed from album and foldered in order of list removed from album.
      - Negative Album 8 - Balkans (Box 27, Folder 81)
        Balkans. Numbered prints removed from album and foldered in order of list removed from album.
      - Negative Album 10 - Corsica, Germany, Holland, Spain (Box 27, Folder 82)
        Corsica, Germany, Holland, Spain. Numbered prints removed from album and foldered in order of list removed from album.
      - Negative Album 11 - India, Japan (Box 28, Folder 83)
        India, Japan. Numbered prints removed from album and foldered in order of list in album.
      - Negative Album 12 - Greece (Box 28, Folder 84)
        Greece. Corresponding prints are in order of list in album.
      - Negative Album 12 - Greece (Box 28, Folder 85)
        Sixteen prints and negatives found with Negative Album 12, not identified in album list.
      - Negative Album 13 - Egypt, Palestine (Box 28, Folder 86)
        Egypt, Palestine. Numbered prints removed from album and foldered in order of list in album.
      - Mexico, Balkans, Egypt, 1936-1938 (Box 29)
    - Negatives -- Slides, 2.3
      Arrangement
      This subseries contains 885 slides ordered alphabetically by location and chronologically within location.
      - Argentina, 1940, 1941, 1942, 1944, 1947, 1948, 1949, undated (Box 30)
      - Bolivia, 1941, 1942, 1944, 1947, 1948, undated (Box 30)
      - Brazil, 1940, 1941, 1949, undated (Box 30)
      - Chile, 1941, 1942, 1947, 1948, 1949, undated (Box 30)
      - Colombia, 1939, 1942, 1947, undated (Box 30)
      - Ecuador, 1941, 1943, 1944, 1948, 1949, undated (Box 31)
      - Mexico, 1947, 1952, undated (Box 31)
      - Panama, 1947-1948 (Box 31)
      - Paraguay, 1941, 1949, undated (Box 31)
      - Peru, 1941, 1942, 1943, 1947, 1948, 1949, undated (Box 31)
      - Uruguay, 1948 (Box 31)
      - Venezuela, 1947, undated (Box 31)
      - Egypt, 1940 (Box 31)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 31)
    - Negatives -- Rolled Negatives, 2.4
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services / Head of Reference.
      - Roll 1 (Box 32)
      - Roll 2 - Egypt / Maine (Box 32)
      - Roll 3 - California (Box 32)
      - Roll 4 - Williamsburg (Box 32)
      - Roll 7 (Box 32)
      - Roll 8 - Colombia - Salto, Chi, Villavicencio, 671 VII (Box 32)
      - Roll 9 - Colombia - Pro Lopez, Panama, 658 VIII (Box 32)
      - Roll 10 - IX Madden dam, Chorrera (Box 32)
      - Roll 11 - X Chorrera Bejuco, S. Carlos, Auton 657 581 (Box 32)
      - Roll 12 - XI Auton, Penonome, Sta Maria, Santiago 670 (Box 33)
      - Roll 13 - Panama / La Guaira (Box 33)
      - Roll 14 - Trinidad / Ceara (Box 33)
      - Roll 15 - Ceara 2 (Box 33)
      - Roll 16 - Ceara / Forteleza (Box 33)
      - Roll 17 - Quixada, Sen Pompeu (Box 33)
      - Roll 18 - Ceara (Box 33)
      - Roll 19 - Ceara (Box 33)
      - Roll 20 - Ceara / R.G. de Norte / British Guiana (Box 33)
      - Roll 21 - British Guiana / Amalfi / Egypt (Box 34)
      - Roll 22 - Egypt (Box 34)
      - Roll 23 - Toronto (Box 34)
      - Rolls 24-28 (Box 34)
      - Rolls 29-37 (Box 35)
      - Rolls 38-46 (Box 36)
      - Rolls 47, 48, 50-56 (Box 37)
      - Rolls 58-60, 62, 63, 66 (Box 38)
      - Rolls 67, 68, 72-76, 79, 82, 83, 86-88 (Box 39)
      - Rolls 89, 90, 92-98 (Box 40)
  - Post Cards, 3
    This subseries contains one box of postcards arranged alphabetically by location. Many postcards have correspondence on the back.
    - Identified, A-Z (Box 41)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 41)
- Oversize, 1689-1957
  - Sketch Map of India, Burma, and Ceylon. Lithograph., MAP (Quantity 1) (Folder 1)
  - Lithograph of Ceylon indicating railways and roads., MAP (Quantity 1); On tissue paper. (Folder 1)
  - "Map of United Provinces." Indicates Malaria distribution in India (color)., MAP (Quantity 1) (Folder 1)
  - "Per La Difesa Dalla Malaria." Public ordinance issued by the municipal government of Rome., 1931 March 12; POSTER (Quantity 1) (Folder 1)
  - Map of Albania, hand-drawn by Italian cartographer Giacomo Cantelli da Vignola., 1689; MAP (Quantity 1) (Folder 1)
  - China Population Distributions (regarding 1945).", 1957; MAP (Quantity 1) (Folder 1)